Guide to the Paul L. Holmer Papers
Yale University Divinity School Library
- Notes by Holmer, n.d.; Series II
  - "Religious Consciousness" - Outline, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 512)
  - "The Rewards of Faith" - Outline - Devotional Material ("Sixth Sunday After Pentecost") (Box 28, Folder 513)
  - "Roman History" - Notes/Outlines ("Life in 1st Century," "Men and Literature," "Chronologies," "Christianity [Why Christianity Spread, etc.]," "What did Jesus say?" "Christianity [Shepherd of Hermas, etc.]," "Christianity [Church Organization]," "Stone Age to Bronze," "Geography and Environment of Italy," "Roman History," "Caesars Reforms," "Post Caesar," "Life in 1st Century," etc. - Other: (completed and graded homework/quizzes) (Box 28, Folder 514)
  - "Romans 3: 19-28" - Outline for lecture given on Reformation Day, Oct. 28, 1990, 1990 Oct 28 (Box 28, Folder 515)
  - "Russell, Bertrand" - Notes/Outlines ("Reflections Inspired by Russell's History of Western Philosophy ," "Russell's Treatment of Dante is Unfortunate," "Notes on Russell's Book," - Article: Review of Bertrand Russell, A History of Western Philosophy, Simon and Schuster, 1945. (Box 28, Folder 516)
  - "Samuel Johnson" - Notes/Outlines ("Johnson's Grammar of Life," "Johnson on Happiness"), n.d. (Box 28, Folder 517)
  - "Samuel Johnson" - Syllabus for "Readings in Samuel Johnson";Notes (Johnson on Religion, Why J. is Studied, J. and Morality, J. as a Critic, J. on Happiness, J. on the Vices and Virtues, J. on Writing, J. as a Philosopher, Luther and Worship); Student Papers by Jay G. Merwin, Jr. ("From Vanity to Satisfaction of Human Wishes," "Johnson's Moral Demands on the Poets," "Why Johnson Bucks the System," "A Johnsonian Approach to the Force of Change"); Letter from Salem Covenant Church (New Brighton, MN); Info about MN historical societies and churches (Box 28, Folder 518)
  - "Seeing As" - Outline, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 519)
  - "The Sermon on the Mount" - Notes/Outlines ("Emotions and the Sermon on the Mount," "About Mourning and Grief," "About Hungering - Thirsting After Righteousness," "About Purity of Heart") (Box 28, Folder 520)
  - "Schweitzer, Albert" - Notes/Outlines ("Schweitzer: The Problems of Peace in the World of Today ," "Notes on Schweitzer," "Albert Schweitzer, the Scholar") - Magazine Clippings ("Greatest Man" - Time 7/11/1949) - Newsletters (Bulletin of the American-Scandinavian Foundation - 4/1979, "To Friends of the UNM [New Mexico] Religious Studies Program - 4/22/1986"), 1945-1986 (Box 28, Folder 521)
  - "Temptation" - Notes/Outlines ("Temptation") - Devotional material ("The First Sunday in Lent") (Box 28, Folder 522)
  - "Temptation and Scholarship" - Notes (Box 28, Folder 523)
  - "Theology and Church Life" - Outlines for a five-part lecture (Box 28, Folder 524)
  - "Theology and Contemporary Learning" (Box 28, Folder #524A)
  - "Theology and the Glory of Being Human" - Outline (Box 28, Folder 525)
  - "Twentieth Century European History" - Notes/Outlines ("Pre-War Europe," "Increase in Nationalism," "Imperialism," Prussia, "Bundesrat," "Austria-Hungary," - etc. Other ("Map Problem No. 1," "Map Problem No. 2," "Cartocraft Desk Outline Map - South and Central Europe") (Box 28, Folder 526)
  - "Two Kinds of Learning" - Outlines (Box 28, Folder 527)
  - "Vices and Virtues" - Notes/Outlines ("Kant and General Ethical Matters," "Virtue for its Own Sake," "Questions About Wisdom," "Question Whether They 'Perfect' Nature," "About Happiness," "Ancient Enumeration of Virtues," "Human Well-Being and Happiness," "About Virtues and Moral Theory," "About Explanations and Emotions," "About 'Unhappiness' in Particular," "Capacity and Concepts," "Lying," "Honesty," "Wisdom," "Happiness," "Sleep and Virtue," "Lying," "Virtue," "Temperance," "Everyday Standards") - Handout ("Selected Ethical Problems) - Other (Class List for Ethics) (Box 28, Folder 528)
  - "Virtues" - Notes/Outlines ("About Intemperance," "On Being Jealous," "On Being Avaricious," "On Being Wise," "About Your Disposition," "About Being a Jumble," "About Your Courage," "About Being Just," "About Being Angry," "On Being Envious," "About the Virtues," "More About Courage," "About Being Temperate," "About Your Troubles," "Theories of Responsibility"), n.d. (Box 28, Folder 529)
  - "Widenman Translation" - Notes, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 530)
  - "Wittgenstein" - Notes/Outlines ("About Philosophy," "Wittgenstein - Drury," "W's Criticisms in P.I. ," "Wittgenstein and Whittaker," "Wittgenstein and Religion," "Wittg. and Theology," short essay on Brothers Karamozov, "Bibliography - Works by Wittgenstein (1889-1951)," "The Wittgenstein Family," "About Wittgenstein," "Criticisms in P.I.," "Wittgenstein and the P.I. ," "In logic, process and result are the same," "A form of life," "Certainty," "S.d. language...," "Logical Questions and Human Action," "W and theology - special points," "On Language," "L.W. and Meaning of Life," "Conclusion," "Wittgenstein's the Blue Book," "About Theology," "What about a private language?" "Engelmann about L.W.," "W's texts on God," "translation," "The use of language to state one's purpose," "Forms of life," "No essence of language game?" "About concepts" (Box 28, Folder 531)
  - "Wittgenstein"- Notes/Outlines ("Daring to be a Subjective Thinker," "Wittgenstein," "W's Tractatus ," "The Tractatus Considered Again," "State of Affairs," "W. and Moral Concepts," "Russell on L.W.," "W's Criticism," "Logic and the World") (Box 28, Folder 532)
  - Wittgenstein: "On Being a Self" - Outlines: "On Being a Self," "Wisdom", n.d. (Box 28, Folder 533)
  - "Wittgenstein on Intention" - Notes/Outlines ("General Issues," "L.W. on 'Intention' - Zettel," "Wittgenstein on Intention," "P.I."), n.d. (Box 28, Folder 534)
  - "Wittgenstein and Religious Belief" - Notes (Box 28, Folder 535)
  - Misc Notes -- "About Religion," "Study of Religion," "General Characterization of Religion," "History of Religions," "India: The Religion of Veda," "Indian Ethics," "Relation of Ethics and Metaphysics," "Comparative Ethics," "Types of Metaphysics in India," "D.M. Datta" (Box 28, Folder 536)
  - Misc. Notes -- "About Seriousness," outline; "Widen Your Heart," outline, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 537)
  - Misc. Notes -- "An Attack Upon the Independence of Theology," notes on Wingren, "Spirituality and Martin Luther" (Box 28, Folder 538)
  - Misc. Notes -- "Biblical and Devotional," "Theological" (Box 28, Folder 539)
  - Misc. Notes -- "Chronological table of Soren Kierkegaard's life and writings" Other: Dorothy M. Emmet's review of Kierkegaard et la philosophie existentielle, Thurston Davis's review of A Short Life of Kierkegaard, Brenda Ueland's article "What Goes On Here," reproductions of portriat of Regina Olsen," pages 2-12 of a paper on problems with modern religious language, page 9 of a paper (possibly a review) on Religion in the Making, pages 13-14 of a paper on Christian devotional literature. (Box 28, Folder 540)
  - Misc. Notes -- "Church," "Persons," "McIntyre," "Luke 16:19-31," "Points About The Point of View ," "Thou Shalt Love Thy Neighbor," "About the Limits of Theology and Philosophy," "Serious Considerations," "Theology: Concepts and Capacities," "Post-Kierkegaard: Remarks About Being A Person" (Box 29, Folder 541)
  - Misc. Notes -- "Comma," "Some New Theses," "Christian Faith and Being Human," pages 2-9 of a dissertation proposal on eschatology neither written by nor addressed to Holmer (e.g., "Dolores joins me in wishing you and Mrs. Piper a flower-filled 'Princeton in the Spring'....") (Box 29, Folder 542)
  - Misc. Notes -- "Conceptual Investigations," "Forms of Life," "Kierkegaard Essays," "About Other Thinkers," "Wittgenstein", n.d. (Box 29, Folder 543)
  - Misc. Notes -- "The Conditions About Jesus of Nazareth," "Esth. Eth. on Marriage," "The Unhappiest Man," "First Editions of S.K.," "Simultanity of Facts [?], "Abs. Paradox," "Ibsen's Dramas," "S.K. was first made known to the European world by...," "Introduction - by Herford," "Epistle to the Reader - Frater Taciturnus ," "The Self-Existent," "Characteristic Manners," "Suppose you have become a subjective teacher," "Passion and Faith," "Absolute Paradox," "The Sin of Pride," "Ethical," "Desperation," "The Essential Expression," "November 5th - 1st Lecture on Kierkegaard," "Notion of misuse of grace-idea," "K. and Ind. Existence," "Theology and Subjectivity," "The human body is the best picture of the human soul," "Possibility and Reality," "K.'s Criticism," "Dialectic," "Stages," "Problem of Truth: Kierkegaard and the Nature of Truth," "K. and Preaching," "Kierkegaard and Neo-Orthodoxy," "Miscellanenus [book/reading list]"Other ("Soren Kierkegaard: List of Dates and Works," "Ethics VIII - The Theory of Punishment," "Chronological Table of Soren Kierkegaard's Life and Writings," "Readings in Soren Kierkegaard," "The Works of Kierkegaard in English," "Kierkegaard Bibliography," "Concerning Soren A. Kierkegaard," "On Meaning" [a Philosophical Theology handout], "Selected Ethical Problems," "'Die Liebe uberbietet fort und sich selbst...': Aus dem Briefwechsel des danischen Philosophen mit Regine Olsen" [an article from Die Zeit - 8/11/1955], letter from Charley on March 6.) (Box 29, Folder 544)
  - Misc. Notes -- "Dates listed in Ouidam's Diary ," "S.K. - Truth and Religion," "Concluding Remarks," "Truth for All Men," "Outline of this chapter - IV," "Theodor Haecker, 'La Notion de la Verite; cheq Soren Kierkegaard dans Essais Sur K., Petrargue, Goethe '," "Uses of History," "K. is 'indirectly communicating'," "The biographical account," "Outline of the Book," "Logic Characterized," "Book Reviews," "Logic and Reality," "Kierkegaard and Logic," "Structure of Human Experience," "Logical Aphorisms," "The Logical Significance of Zeno's Paradoxes," "Negative relation to the objective order [logic]," "True knowledge and true reality," "Voltaire," "First concerning some necessary details," "Science and Religion - A Classified Bibliography," excerpt from essay on educational philosophy. (Box 29, Folder 545)
  - Misc. Notes -- Doubt (notes and preface to Tad Stashwick's paper "On Descartes and Conquering Doubt"), Self-Knowledge, Virtues, notes on Engelman's Letters, "Mistakes and Conjectures" (Box 29, Folder 546)
  - Misc. Notes -- "Education and the Liberal Arts," "On Being Conscious," "Vices and Virtues," "Kant's Moral Philosophy" (Box 29, Folder 547)
  - Misc. Notes -- Emotion (notes from J. Middleton Murry's The Problem of Style ), God, Truth, Myths, C.S. Lewis; Letters from Donald Dayton (K. Barth Society of N.A.), Keith R. Bridston, Dennis Nyberg (San Ramon Valley UMC--Alamo, CA); Info for Symposium in Rhetoric (Denton, TX); Articles: "About Emotions and Passions," "Meaning and Praying," "Learning How to Be Religious: The Work of Paul of Holmer" (by Patrick Sherry) (Box 29, Folder 548)
  - Misc. Notes -- "Faith is a Disposition of the Human Heart," "Wanting," "The Logic of the Self," "The Harmony Between Thought and Reality," "Use of the Word of God," Meaning, "Christianity and Making Sense," "Making Sense Christianly: Volition," "God and the Virtues," "Will," "Notes on Rural Matters," "Self-Understanding," "Believing in God," "What God Can't Do," "Understanding One's Actions," "Tolstoy as an Artist," Bates, "Emotions and Macbeth ," "Picture of Being a Thinker - Wm. James," Philosophy, "'God is a concept ... Dorothy Day," "God," "Plato's tale - peril of choosing," "Possibility - Actuality," "Shame," "Virtue," "Possibility and Actuality," "Topics for Papers and Sermons," "Knowing the Self," "Self-Knowledge," "Vices and Virtues," "Will," "Happiness," "Will," "Phil. Criticism and Theology," "Philosophical Criticism and Theology," "Com. Bible: Message," "Quality," "Virtue," "Human Life and Search for Satisfation," "Augustine Confessions ," "Wise as Serpents and Harmless as Doves," "What Do We Make of Jesus?" "M. Luther and J. Wesley," "Dismantling Our Pride," "Intending the World as Xians: The Church," "Transf. Power of Otherworldliness" Short essay -- Professions short essay; Letters -- Rev. Franklin Sherman - Oxford -10/11/65, from Holmer to "Hal"; Other -- transcript of lecture on "Religious Talk' from tape (Box 29, Folder 549)
  - Misc. Notes -- "Introduction," "Trad. Topics," "Sugg. Topics," "Explaining/Knowing," "Understanding/Justifying/Living/Believing" (Box 29, Folder 550)
  - Misc. Notes --"Kierkegaard and the Sermon" (title page), "The Nature of Rel. Prop.," list of essays, table of contents, "K. and Communication," "Concerning Preaching," "Kierkegaard and Preaching," "Chapter IV - Metaphysics and Personality," "Kierkegaard and Metaphysics" Other -- pages 3-19 of a paper on logic, pages 21-35 of a paper about S.K., pages 64-67 of a paper on S.K., pages 224-229 of a paper on S.K., pages of 257-267 of a bibliography from a paper on S.K., pages of 265-267 of the same bibliography, page 9 of a paper on S.K. (Box 29, Folder 551)
  - Misc. Notes -- "Learning for Leadership - About Your Disposition," "Learning for Leadership - About Being Just," "we cannot promise that there are some secrets that will make everything better in the future," "Life of the Human Spirit," "Sin," letter from Roger R. Boyer, "Culture and Value," "The Human Condition: Moral and Religious Considerations," "Concerning the Human Condition," "danger of idolatry," "Living the Christian Life: Contemporary Society," "Life of the Human Spirit," "Lect. of Oct. 1996," "The Human Condition: Moral - Religious Consideration," "Making a Life: general remarks," "Learning," "Funeral of a Great Myth," "Some Dicta," "Lewis - Emotion," "Lewis and the Imagination," "About 'Taste' and 'Likes'," "What Lit. Is and Does," "Personal Heresy," "About Literature and its Criticism," "About Language and Literature Again," Lewis and pleasures, "Modern Man and Categories of Thought," "Modern Man and Categories of Thought," "Imagination," "C.S. Lewis: The Man and His Career" (Box 29, Folder 552)
  - Misc. Notes -- "Logical Problems," "Theology and Knowledge of God," "Language and Understanding," "Language and 'Expression'," "Language: Expression and Understanding," "About Philosophical Theology," "Scandal of Theology," "Faith and its Logical Geography," "The Purposes of Theology," "The Theological Situation," "Supernaturalism," "Facts - Disclosures," Notes from the Ramsey Lectures, "'God is Dead' Theologians," "For Self-Examination," "Certainty and Uncertainty," "Concerning the Religious Consciousness," "Understanding and Language," "Alienated Man," Tolstoi, Bible, Wittgenstein, Concepts, Historical Facts, "Syst. Ambiguity and Facts," "Ambiguity - Systematic and Otherwise," "Two Kinds of Tasks," "Plato on Ideas," "Phil. Arguments," "On Learning Xian Concepts" (Box 29, Folder 553)
  - Misc. Notes/other -- "Luther thought that a major need of his day..." pages 2-24 of that paper, pages 16-20 of a paper on S.K., page 75 of a bibliography, pages 223 and 226 of the chapter "Logic and Existence," page 256 from a bibilography for a paper on S.K., page 14 of a paper on S.K., "About Lewis," page 4 of a paper on logic (Box 29, Folder 554)
  - Misc. Notes -- "Newman on Special Topics," "Readings for 'Renewal of the Church...'," "Science and Religion," "Lutheran Criticism of Devotional Practice," "Dogma and the Catholic Church," "John Calvin," sermon on II Cor. 4:16, bibliography, "Phil. and the Common Life," "Language and Meanings," "On Understanding," "Are Religious Concepts Outmoded?" faith, "Beliefs - Creeds - and Holiness," "Crisis in Humanities," "Topics and Readings," "The Relations Between Beliefs - Creeds and Holiness," "Special Topic," "Lutherans and Philosophy," "Kierkegaard and Logic," "Tillich: L and Meaning," "Theology and Understanding," "About Understanding and Religious Belief," "Nygren and Linguistic Analysis," "The Concept of God in Whitehead," "What is Metaphysics?" "On What There Is," "'Anselm in Argument' ac. to Malcolm," "Anselm's Second Argument"Article: Untitled essay on emotions, beginning "Emotions are physiological; thoughts are mental." Other excerpts from essays/articles. Prayer: Short prayer beginning "O Lord, we have a busy world around us." (Box 29, Folder 555)
  - Misc. Notes -- "Notes on Kierkegaard's Parity of Heart ," "K.: A Modern Cultural Force," "Existential Pathos," "S.K. and the Nature of Theology," "God as Teacher and Savior: An Essay of the Imagination," "C of D," "Faith and Theology," "Repetition," "Concepts Given Special Treatment in K. Literature," "How I See Theology," "On Authority and Revelation," "Disciples at 2nd Hand," "Concepts re: Xianity"Article: "Soren Kierkegaard: Faith and Paradox" - Chapter: Revised copy of first page of "Chapter II: The Authorship Considered"Handouts: "Readings in Soren Kierkegaard," "Works of Soren Kierkegaard, in order of Publication" (Box 29, Folder 556)
  - Misc. Notes -- "Obj. Uncertainty and Human Faith," "In the Spirit of Kierkegaard" [an addresss at YDS], Certainty, "Systematic Ambiguity," "Living With Passions," "The Obj. Problem of the Truth of Xianity," "Argument of the Postscript," "Truth is Subjectivity," "W.'s Negative Thesis," "Theology and Scripture," "Truth is Subjectivity," "About Pleasure" (Box 29, Folder 557)
  - Misc. Notes -- "On Believing in Philosophical Concepts," "Is Xianity Obsolete?" "God's Nature - Unchangeableness," "Science and Religion," "Educating Our Dispositions," "Christology," "On Believing in Philosophical Concepts," "On Concepts - Emotions and the Religious Life" Article: "Functions of Intelligence" (delivered May 1934 by ?) Collected Material: John 6:22-64; Letter: From Will "WGO" on 9/15/70, Re: An AAR Monograph (Box 29, Folder 558)
  - Misc. Notes -- "On Fear," "Cont[emporary] Theol. and the Preacher," "About Interpret[ing] Scripture" (Box 29, Folder 559)
  - Misc. Notes -- "Original Sin and Virtues," "Generalities," "Interdependence of Virtues," "About Self," "Plato's Gorgias ," "Virtues and Vices," "Theology," "Virtues," "Consciousness," "Imagination," "Self-Knowledge," "Love of God," "Relations," "Suggested Essays," "About Literary Criticism," "Plato's Charmides ," "Happiness," "Grief," virtue, ideas about God, "Knowledge and Virtue," "About the Tragic," "About Understanding ... Faith," "Repitition of the Self," "A Note About 'Explanation' and Ourselves," "Despair," "Envy," T.S. Eliot, "Comedy," living and believing, "From a Human Point of View," "On Being a Minister," "M. Luther," "Thinking and Doing," Edith Wharton, Philippians 4:4, "Kant on Happiness," "Imagination," "Theology and Grammar," "The Conception of Ourselves (Rom. 6:3)," creation, "About God and People," "About What People Are," "About the Virtues," "Wanting," "Belief and Knowledge," "Irony," "About Emotions and Feelings," "Emotions, Feelings and Beliefs," "Criteria of Adequacy for a Doctrine of God" - Untitled Essay: beginning with the line "There is a way, too in which Kierkegaard is protesting general epistemology." (Box 29, Folder 560)
  - Misc. Notes -- "Paradoxe," "Tr. in Xianity," "Kierkegaard and the New Way of Philosophizing," "Contemporaneity," "Christian Def. of Concepts" (Box 30, Folder 561)
  - Misc. Notes -- "Petition for a Seminar to Executive Comm. of the A.A.R." (Topic of Seminar: Wittgenstein and the Study of Religion); notes on "The Minister, A Reconsideration"; various excerpts from longer papers (Box 30, Folder 562)
  - Misc. Notes -- Positivism (outline), About Christianity and Art (outline) (Box 30, Folder 563)
  - Misc. Notes -- sermons and preaching, outline on "faith and belief" - page 3 of a longer outline (Box 30, Folder 564)
  - Misc. Notes -- S.K. on existence [essay abstract], existence rough outline, "paradox and faith," "passion and faith," "S.K. on Subjectivity and Truth," "Moment is Decisive - Moment is an Occasion," "Existential Pathos," "Choose an Esthetician," "Remarks About Art - Faith - Thought," "Notion of Taste and Beauty (18th century)," art and intention, "About Virtues and Emotions and Charity," "About Philosophical Ways," "Some Phil. Reflections About Theology," "Austin on 'Perfection Utterances'," "Performative Utterances," confusion, "Nature of Philosophy," "About Conceptual Systems," "Notion that facts 'are' facts," "'True' and 'Truth'" (Box 30, Folder 565)
  - Misc. Notes -- "Relgions and Becoming a Self," "About Hinduism," "Judaism," "Mohammed and Islam" - Membership information for the St. Paul University Club (Box 30, Folder 566)
  - Misc. Notes -- "Swenson's Letter to K.S. Lashley," "The Ontolog. Problem," "The Nature of Man," "Typical Problems in Phil. of Religion," "History of X'n Doctrine," "Does God Act in Human History?" "'How' of office," "Topics for discussion: fall and winter quarters 1959-1960 Philosophy of Religion Seminar: Professor Paul L. Holmer," "Creation in Science," "Creation in Judeo-Christian Context," "Language of Faith and Science," "God - 11/11/1942," "The Thomists and Scotists - Two Schools," "Medieval World - Picture," "Theology in the Twentieth-Century," "Phil. in the West," "The Problem of Meaning," "A Project of Thought," "Feuslee," "Is Faith Knowledge?" "I.M. Crombie again," - Handouts -- "Kierkegaard and Logic," "The Old and the New," "Course in Metaphysics: Sheldon," "Philosophy of Religion," "R.B. Braithwaite - 'Empericists View of the Nature of Rel. Belief'," "Schleiermacher on Ethics," "Religion and Doubt and Despair," "Tillich's Mistaken Endeavor," "Soren Kierkegaard - Maker of Modern World," "The Language of Faith," "Quanity increases - quality never?" "Criteria of Adequacy for a Doctrine of God" (Box 30, Folder 567)
  - Misc. Notes -- theism/atheism paper -- pages 3-10, sin, Screwtape/The Devil, pages 6-24 of a paper on capacities, page 14 of a paper on S.K. which covers the concepts of "dialectical contradictions" and "the paradoxical" (Box 30, Folder 568)
  - Misc. Notes -- "Tillich on God's Existence," on Norman Sykes, Waismann, "Concept," "Concept of Suffering," "Special Articles for Phil. Theology," "The New Theology II," "Absence of Belief," "One Kind of Context for Saying God Exists," "Man is not conscious of guilt because he sins but sins because he is conscious of guilt," "Stewards of Mysteries," "Isaiah 45: 'Truly, thou art a God who hidest thyself'," "Faith: Meaning and Saying," "Where are present phil. and theol. going?" John Wesley, "Meaning Again," "Faith as a Dispisition," "Peace and Advent," "Walter Stroomseth," "The Fellowship of Mystery," "Peace and Christian Faith," "Some Thoughts on Relig. Educ.," "Wittgenstein and New Hermeneutical Theology," "Points for an address," "We Have This Treasure in Earthen Vessels," "Meaning It" (Box 30, Folder 569)
  - Misc. Notes -- "Tractatus," "Picture Theory," "About W. Again," Logic, "Logic is transcendental," "W. on 'the world of the happy man," "Tractatus," "About Tractatus," "The Form of an object," "About L.W. 1889-1951" (Box 30, Folder 570)
  - Misc. Notes -- understanding happiness, what theology is, page four of an unknown outline (Box 30A, Folder 571)
  - Misc. Notes -- understanding and worldliness, page 37 of a paper on Christian love, page 15 of a paper on faith and the possibility for (or lack of) transforming power in scholarly truth, "about 'pedagogy'," "Soren Kierkegaard and Ludwig Wittgenstein: Any Conflicts," "Kierkegaard and Wittgenstein," "K. and W.: Any Conflicts," "Some Substantive Issues in Common," "Obscurity," chapter list, "Outline of Chapter I," "Outline of Chapter II," "Outline of Chapter III," "Outline of Chapter IV," "The Virtues," "Emotion and Religion," "Happiness," "Grace," "The Changing Conception of the Person: Misadventures and Misgivings," "Remarks About M. Buber," "Vengence is Mine," "Preaching and the Contemporary Believer," "The Shape of Christian Action," "Emotions," "Ordinary Language," "Some Generalities About Emotions" - Other: Excerpts of "The Transforming Power of Otherworldiness," from The Faith of a Scholar (Box 30A, Folder 572)